meeting of the Miami City Council for today's daytime time. I am
to the Minister of the Office for Rudy Schroffs and Vicki Lewis, suckers.
You want to stay there, you want to come down?
Hey, whatever you think is bad.
It's like that.
Oh, this is good.
I think it's not going to be a good one.
I think we're going to want to watch Vicki down this morning.
I would really love to see this one.
I feel good.
Someone's convincing me?
Thank you.
Sorry.
– I'm sorry.
You have something to say?
Well, thank you.
Didn't you know, I mean, we've been getting married in the air of Mary's Feve, Betha,
and Arthur, producing Ricky Budger, I hand please.
Right?
Where do you sell, it's on this, direct to?
I really, sure.
To support the day and defend the constitution, the oil, how did they,
uh.
That's the standard of the Constitution of the State of Oklahoma.
And the Constitution of the State of Oklahoma.
And that I will not knowingly receive correctly or indirectly,
anybody who are about equal things.
And I will not know if we have some directly or indirectly
in the money or not.
But the performance or not reports of any act or duty
for getting to my office for the performance
along the forms of any act or duty.
Other than the compensation, a lot of Bible.
I have been in the zero office.
I took that book.
I've heard of this prayer or a form.
I've heard of this letter from that I will
faithfully discharge according to the best of my ability.
I will faithfully discharge according to the best of my ability.
The duties of my office during such times,
as I served as the mayor of the city of Miami.
I do this a while to such times as I served as the mayor of the city of Miami.
As the mayor of the city of Miami.
And chairman of the board, the president of the Miami special
to be paid for.
And the board of trustees in Miami special in California.
As the city of Miami of the city of Miami.
I'm so glad you're still in the district.
Thank you.
I will take you.
Take you.
Take you with us.
Take you so you get all the work being rejected.
Take you that.
Take me.
You.
Take you.
Son.
Are we.
Do you have it.
I just think about the state in the state of.
Whatever the state of my school.
and I act for doing an entertaining to my office.
But the performance or not, the performance will be me after doing entertaining to my office.
I did them in compensation a lot by law.
I did them in the compensation a lot by law.
I further swear or a foreign.
And I will faithfully discharge according to the best of my ability.
I will faithfully discharge according to the best of my ability.
the duties of my office during such time as I am the member of the city of the Miami City Council.
To duties of my office during such time as I am a member of the Miami City Council,
more forward, more forward, and the Board of Trustees and the Miami Special Utility Authority.
And the Board of Trustees of the Miami Special Utility Authority.
Of the city of Miami, more forward.
At the city of Miami, the moment.
Congratulations.
Thank you.
I really need to sign in.
I've got to register.
Okay.
We are going to move on to the right agenda and follow me.
We want to item three, which is public input and schedule personal interviews.
And I want to ask you which is to address the council on any of the agenda items.
You're being nine.
I have a four as a consent agenda staff.
It's recommending items five through nine, but I think Neil has one.
We're going to fill the planes out first.
Right.
Take it away from there.
And I'd like to go motion to prove item six, seven, eight in the consent agenda.
And I'm going to press.
Okay.
I've got a question in regards to item seven on our parks and rack.
Is that just a cleanup on the permit facility use permit?
Yes.
Yeah.
Is it just some warning cleaning up up?
So let's go and pull that one up.
Yeah.
Sure.
So item six and nine in.
Uh, yes.
I'm like like a motion to put those out.
Second.
Don't call.
Johnson.
High.
Western.
Forester.
High.
Lewis.
Okay.
Just pick out a five or a quick first.
You may talk about it.
You want to.
Yeah.
I'm going to claim there is an item for.
Was it capital services?
Yeah.
Capital services.
Which is a lot of inform that we use for some of our federal issues.
The current mayor of Tulsa at one time served work for that farm and he along with Stuart McAllman.
And Stuart was supposed to come down and try to get down prior to this meeting and meet with the other council members.
Dean.
I had a meeting with him and Tulsa a couple of weeks ago with one of us and a half staff talking about trying to get money for raising Steve Owen and some other projects.
But since he's not been able to come yet.
Neil has asked that we pull that particular invoice that one and not pay it and hold it until Stuart's table will come down.
And talk with the rest of the council about his services that he provides.
Um, et cetera.
And we can make an informed decision on how we want to move forward with his firm.
I understand technically you're wanting to table the item.
I want to table that in like I said earlier that I would like the opportunity for all of us to talk to him.
And we have our budget coming up next week and that would be a good time to.
May or may not proceed with this.
I don't know.
So table in all of that.
I'll take puts it on the next agenda, as opposed to just taking no action, so I don't care.
I'm just pointing out the distinct number.
Okay, so then you want to make a motion to table that item.
Right, okay.
Do we have a second?
Second.
Will I call a police?
Johnson.
Aye.
Four stars.
Lewis, aye.
Weston.
All right.
Now, we'll have a motion to prove the rest of the claims.
You do.
As president.
And second.
Will I call a police?
Johnson.
Weston.
Lewis.
Aye.
Schofer.
Forbister.
Sorry.
Aye.
Schofer.
And then item.
7.
Approved.
For Parks and Wack.
James.
Can you come up with a question?
I'd like to ask Brian's question.
I'll ask him.
My question is.
What brought this up?
Is it just adjusting some of the warning?
It's going to be a set contract for everyone, so for the programs that comes in.
And it's just specifically for the Fairgrounds events that are taking place up.
Correct.
All right.
Okay.
If I can ask a little bit, we had the monster truck event, I think.
And I use that opportunity to allow John Jan to look at the template we're using.
And so she recommended.
Right.
I mean, it's a change as of.
Wouldn't so much in the cost as it was.
The warning of contract.
That's all I need to do.
Okay.
Thank you.
Yep.
Okay.
Great.
I appreciate Chris.
You have enjoyed being looking back.
Make sure we're.
Got an honor.
Eyes dotted.
T's cross.
So do we have a motion to approve items.
Question.
Second.
Roll call please.
Forster.
Aye.
Louis.
Western.
Johnson.
Short.
Aye.
Item.
Two.
Is.
A minute.
Current agreement with the internet service product.
Both to include its hosting of a digital phone system.
Hi, David.
Hi.
First time.
I've been on this side of the mic.
I guess to give you some background on this.
Last year.
Physical year.
16.
17.
We actually budgeted.
$86,000 to replace our phone system.
The current system in the 16.
Plus years old.
And frankly, like anything that's technology that's 16 years old, there's things to
broken and they just don't work anymore.
We had a committee of five employees that looked at numerous systems.
And we found pretty quickly that going with the hosted system was going to be more cost effective.
Then having any on-premises service that we owned.
If you found a unique situation with bolts and state, provide internet and phone service,
they have a business service that's.
posted for the phone system.
And by going with them and expanding our agreement with them,
we can see an immediate savings.
Yearly of approximately $45,000,
based on what we're paying for AT&T services.
And what I'm building for you tonight
is the actual purchasing of the initial system,
which would not exceed 45,000, $864 in the 65 cents.
My hope is that it will actually be lower than that number,
because after we get this approved,
we can go through it and really look at
whether we need every single phone
that we've got with the way the new system works.
I would like to have just a clarification,
not only for the council, but anybody watching.
I made the announcement about working with both
to come into my end of the Vulcan command and serve entities.
And they are currently serving us right now.
So if you're wondering about,
if this is related to bringing both in on the fiber system,
they're completely different issues.
I just wanted to make that very clear.
Do they supply the phones?
Yes.
Yes, it's a tiny phone.
There's a lot of technical support.
Yes, if we had these phones when we purchased them,
we'll start out having a three-year warranty.
So if something happens to it,
they just send us a new phone.
On top of that, if we have any issues with setup
or any of our facilities, they would have the support.
We would call them and they would fix it.
Much like half, we have a problem with AT&T, AT&T,
as who comes out and fixes the still items.
So David has a little confused by your second part of your answer.
Because I'm looking also researching the OIP systems right now.
I know there's different models out there.
I'll be actually purchasing the heart, the telephone set,
and then paying them for...
Yes, three-year issue service.
Yes, what we'll be doing is we would actually
on the actual second part of this,
which is the actual coat they sent.
The coat is broken onto the non-reaccurring charges,
and the monthly recurring charges.
The non-reaccurring charges are the individual charges
for the hand sets, as well as the equipment
to tie in to their network to supply our dial tone.
One of the things I think being mentioned earlier
is like the city of grove and all of that.
Have you talked to any other municipalities
that use them as for their phone service?
I haven't talked to any municipalities that have used both
for phone service, but I have talked to individuals
and a few businesses that have used them for phone service.
And early on in this process, I did contact a 10 on the East Coast
that used an IP service, and that's one of the things
that led me to determine that a hosted service would actually.
service and we would not have issues with quality. That's to say it was not bought that they
were using on these coasts. Would you help me with my math? We had a 6,000 budgeted for this
basically you're right. So what are you trying to tell us? What's an additional cost to this or
I'm having to tell you. The additional cost would be the same thing that we have, like with AT&T,
we would have a monthly bill and that would be approximately 5,400. That would be the monthly charge for the
dial tone. In comparison, our charge is just for the civics on our loan. AT&T is 7,369 dollars,
just to have the dial tone in the civics center. We have about six other bills that's, I took
to say that you have to make the initial investment in the estimate. And that was what we budgeted the
86,000 for one. And we budgeted 86,000, but it looks like it's only going to take 45 now. Yes, that's what
we're going to say 30,000. Yes, we're going to say 35,000 would be an immediate savings off of what we had budgeted
out of that money. That's what we're saving money. Yeah, yeah. We're saving money on buying the system and we're saving
money on the month. You're working your budget really well. Yeah, I'm 35,000 and we appreciate it.
I mean, it was a lot of work for it and get sucked up too much. You get to have some of that. Thank you for
doing that. Yeah, yeah. You feel that this is a reliable. Yes, everyone I am Dr. Zed, it's a very reliable service.
I mean, frankly, since we've had both providing our internet, we've had less outages here in the civic
center on our internet versus their cable lines. And that would probably be a plus to the city to
have internet and phone services with the same company. Yes, yes, it would. Can they bundle that?
I don't know about. They can't make a phone as far as I know, but I don't know that it would be a little
button. I'm sure they could, but you see we're already a internet service. Okay, we should have to maintain
a few analog lines for. Yes, we'll have some analog lines for facts I'm shooting and we will also have
some analog lines as emergency backup. If we did have an issue that cost an average, someone would be able to
call that number and someone at the city would pick up the phone. And also this is not 911. No, this is
not 911. That's a totally separate service. Right. A really great job. Thank you. Okay, so is there any
is this an action item or so we need to amend the current agreement? Is what you're asking for?
Yes, we approve a meeting in the current agreement. Can you make a motion? And second. I'll
say a little call, please. Forster Johnson, Lewis, I Weston. All right. Thank you very much, do.
Any business?
No.
OK.
Mayor Councillor Nelson is getting.
I know you had something.
Excuse me, Neil.
Just a quick update on a real-year-risk weekend
from my fifth and sixth.
Last I heard, they're 19, right to the law,
and part of Michael D'Sauze.
And all the past buildings, they might do it to Saturday
and Sunday instead of Friday and Saturday.
I don't think that decision would probably be made
until tomorrow, or possibly the last Thursday, maybe
I've just done it now.
But that's the last I heard on it.
And it's up to the weather.
Yeah.
I had one question in regards with our current situation
with the water.
The gentleman, the organization that's doing the drilling
down at the park, were they able to get everything
moved out of the way, all their pipes or anything?
No issues there.
I haven't contacted them about having any issues.
I've been down there.
I see other equipment by the big pool.
So I think they just had to wait it out.
I saw them there.
They were moving in their boring unit one day.
They hadn't gone across the bridge, actually.
OK.
I need for Dean.
We'll have both of those under our reports.
I've asked Chief Anderson to kind of give an update on where we're at
right now.
Then also I received a call from Dan Sullivan.
One that you go ahead and do your report and then I'll follow up
after you.
OK.
Currently, we're, we also requested in college at 21.94.
It is forecasted to fall to just over 20.25.
However, we are anticipating rain tonight tomorrow.
And they do think it's going to go back up to 21.2.
So we just a little bit low in the morning right now.
And stay below.
It'll probably low flood stage, which is 15.
Late Saturday evening.
I think the problem we really do incur is flash flooding.
Right now, obviously there's no place for water to go because we're pretty
saturated and every, everything's full.
If we do get rain or flash flooding, I think maybe a little bit worse than normal.
Just because that water has no place to go.
We have had significant traffic issues.
Intern, obviously, with the other major highways cut off,
Steve Owens.
I have a 125 central.
And then elementary.
The high school was a challenge for school today.
They go around 16 on a and then back in the town to get to school.
And we have had officers working traffic on the evening.
It's been a very congested and several traffic backups.
And we've had assistance from Auto County Sheriff's Office.
A couple of trial-related disease.
we're just getting every candidate to have a go and put one way in my town. It's been a challenge to drive traffic.
One of the roughest intersections to have to get traffic in an out of town is the one that we really want to do work in.
And it's a good thing we get trapped in.
I'll also point out that today with this I have been in touch with representative lowering and senator Bergstrom.
We're finding them that this was one of the reasons why we were wanting to do the feasibility study of raising 125.
I've been here two and a half years. This is now the fourth time we've had to close off 125.
And I understand that they're going to make some contacts. I'm hoping maybe we will get that off center.
Also, speaking of at least I have our meeting in the morning. Yes, we do.
I've been canceled at all. And that's with grand gateway to see if they might be able to help us find some alternative funding for 125 as well.
Also speaking of Stuart McCallman of capital ventures I've also been in contact with him because one of the things we've asked him to do is to start working on trying to get funding for raising Steve Owens.
So it would be above the situation again and two and a half years here. This is the second time now we've had to close Steve Owens.
And Stuart is working on that. Of course, we are working with the primarily senator in-haw staff.
But he'll be working with other congressional staffers as well.
This identifies the fact that this is much more current than is going on in these rain events are becoming much more common.
Along that line two I want to point out that at five o'clock I received a call from Dan Sullivan, the chairman of GRDA.
Dan informed me that throughout the evening they intend to keep up discharges that Pensacola dam of about 131,000 cubic feet per second.
That's about a million gallons a second. It is what's being discharged right now through Pensacola.
They did say that it's the lake level goes down.
Their discharges will probably start slowing down so they may open a few other gates because they're going right now to keep up the level of 131,000 cubic feet per second.
By morning they'll probably have an idea of where they stand and make decisions about what gate changes they may make and they'll be informing us.
And just as the chief was indicating the wild card right now is that rain system was being predicted to come through.
I think the National Weather Service is still saying upwards of two inches that could fall on the Missouri Oklahoma border.
I think there's been that some other predictions that might move a little farther over towards Springfield instead of hitting us.
If that happens I'll be happy but my friends in Branson will not because that's their system and they're flooding just as badly if not worse than we are right now.
So that's what we're having to do to deal with that.
So I think there's a little bit less than what they were discharging during the flooding that we had in December of 2015.
Give you a little bit of a second.
That's about 7.4.
There were gallons in every cubic foot of water, so you multiply that out as about 980,000.
That gives you an idea of the amount of water that is coming through my amma, coming through
the spring river system, going in to Grand Lake, and being discharged, and of course, below
that in Lake Hudson, I think they're just charging about 100,000 cubic feet per second.
But the core of engineers, of course, is trying to balance it out as to what everything is
going into the Arkansas river system.
So, it's widespread flooding, so that's a report at this point.
Did you get me a good news for me?
Ben's a slutty.
I don't know if you can.
We're just trying to get me a good news.
I know that ODOT is saying that they are contemplating going to be suspending some of the projects
that they're already working on.
So, that does not sound very promising for us with regards to our project on 1.5.
Ben, on the news this morning, I saw that ODOT announced that there was a bridge project in Tulsa
that they have suspended.
Is that a wrong outline?
I, yes.
OK.
I was wondering if that might have been the reason.
Projects will mention that that's what they were saying, it's looking like they're going to have to do
it.
OK.
Anybody from ODOT would like to come down and see in real time some of our struggles right now.
I'd be more than willing to give them a turn.
OK.
I'll tell you, ODOT is the one that closed off Steve Don't want to say, they're just
asked for the ones that put up those barricades.
OK.
Do you know if you want to put them all up?
Yeah.
OK.
Anything else?
Some of our night start, no Thursday night starts the farmers market.
Yeah.
Good.
And there's also a press there inside of all things because they're trying to get the project
and it gives me another thing.
And if anybody hasn't had a chance to look at the murals as part of mural fest, please drive
down central, that I'm so sorry that it rained all that day because I think it would have
been one heck of a party, but they're already planning for a mural fest next year and I believe
it's not going to do it.
Yes, they did.
And I think they're planning next year to be downtown.
So, Neil, speaking of craft fairs, I know that originally planned this part of the road
there was going to be.
Is that still going to happen?
Yeah.
And it's all dependent on the water.
And the wild car right now is that rain that we either may or may not get over that couple days.
Yeah.
And to touch on your murals, it is beautiful.
And you know, we just like let most people know that, you know, we agreed to allow a lot of that stuff.
We don't want some intermedia who can be part of the season.
We're not going out and doing any great right?
Great.
I'm sorry.
I also think it needs to be known that the city did not pay for that.
Right.
I don't know.
People are saying, what do you mean the city is paying for the murder?
And we did not, that was not part of the city.
We were doing in kind support, our utilities, funds, our street department.
We helped in some areas of closing our street, putting barricades, things such as that.
But the actual project itself, paying for the utilities that they used to know about, that's
all being paid for by the festival, not by the city.
Okay.
We're on to the next item, which is adjourned.
Do we have a motion to adjourn?
Motion to adjourn?
I'm singing in roll call, please.
So we're starting?
Aye.
We were, uh, western?
All right.
We have stuff to sign.
We're always done.